Hello programmer welcome back to to this and other tutorial topic. So today we will explore the
exist operator in the post-screen SQL. And the exist apart in post-screen allows us to check the
sub query returns. And this is commonly used the conjunction with the correlated sub query to
perform the conditional logic based on the existence of the row. Okay. So first of all, I can
simply just use the example for retrieving the list of the customer table or the price of the car
table is greater than 40 log. Okay. So first of all here I'll clear the data query for the syntax
so here type for select here multiplication sign for here the customer table and here the
why we can use this. So now this is type the exist so X is t. Okay. So now we have for the parenthesis
and in this here I can create the semicolon. Okay. And now here instead I can create for the
data query. So first of all, I can again use the select from the price for from the table it is called
the cursor now. Here I can use again this is why first of all this the car dot id. Okay. It's equal
to so here I can choose for the customers dot id. And here I can use for the end operator and type
perfectly this price is greater than four here the two log. Okay. So here perfectly just
completely create here. And now just check. So first of all, I'm going to select for the customer
stable. Okay. And adjust and select for the price from the customer stable. I know the cursor
did for the customers ID and now complete and here I can select and execute and now I can
the storage and you can see here perfectly see the result and here the operation is perfectly
successful. And here the post is return for the table information from the ID inserted the 25 and
Mumbai and 25 and here the more fee for output for the result setting to table. Okay.
So the next step here I can use for the exit operator with the update statement. Okay.
So now just try. So here I'll use for the suppose modify the name of the
all the customers whose ID is equal to the ID of the first table. Okay. So here first of all,
I'm going to use the statement. So first of all, here I can use for the update. So
just I can remove this first of all here I can type this update for the customer and now
remove for this and here I can type this set of name is equal to here. I can use for the name
for a specific name for crucial. Okay. So create you. It's not now. Okay.
US 8L the crucial end here. Now I'm going to this step. So now use for y then not it is perfect and
why I still so exist and create the parenthesis and now in this inside, I'll just select from
just remove this and first of all here I can again just remove. Okay. So here I can use for the
word of exist and now here I can type this select from name and here I can use from the
constable and this is the where this is a. Okay. So the customers dot ID and is
equal to so first of all, I can type the car store ID. Okay. So now here simply just create the
perfectly and here I can just create in this code. So now first of all here, update the customer
set for the name of the crucial and where the exist for the select names from okay. So now I can
try execute and you can see simply the table. So now here I can try for this code. Okay.
So now here this is perfectly type this code and here the data query then I can select the
execute and now you can see the table is perfectly affected. Okay. So now I can verify this
at this table. So another new query and here first of all, I can just type this is the select
from and here I can use for the star and then first of all, I can use for the
customer table. So you can choose here the customer table and now just here select and execute.
Now you can see here the crucial for the perfectly update and now here we can open for another
table. So now the type select here from here called the first table. Okay. So defined for here
perfectly and now the select and execute and you can see here perfectly update the
completely used information. Okay. So here perfectly update for the statement and here I can
completely use for the exist operator in the post-screen SQL. Okay. So I hope you perfectly
understand this session. So thank you for watching and happy coding.